英会話タイムトライアル
Let's get started with Day 11 for the month of October.
Hi, everyone.
I'm Steve Sarese.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore.
Thanks for joining us.
Welcome to a new week of Eikaiwa Time Trial.
英語でつながる船の旅
あなたは今月アイルランドに来ています。
We're in Ireland.
今週金曜日の対話カロッケでは、こんな場面で会話をします。
Here's your conversation partner from Ireland.
Welcome to week three.
Nora here.
I have a special treat for you.
Let's have a full Irish breakfast.
It's one of the most famous things to do in Ireland.
We will go to a nice little restaurant in Dublin on Friday.
See you then.
Thanks, Nora.
アイドランドならではの朝ごはん、ブレックフェスト。
それが会話の場面になります。
ということで、今週も引き続き、
食や料理にまつわる表現を練習していきましょう。
今回はレストランに入って席に着くまでの
一連の流れを英語で表現してみます。
レストランの雰囲気を想像しながら楽しく練習しましょう。
Let's have some fun and practice some new phrases together.
You'll feel like you're going to a restaurant with us.
それでは、1回目の挑戦です。
It's time for your first try.
S-P-R-R-A-N-G-I-N-G
日本語を時間内に英語で表現してください。
Here's the first one.
このアイロランド料理店は味がありますね。
あまり知られていませんが、料理がおいしいです。
レストランの外にいつも行列ができています。
Long line あるいは long queue を使って言ってみよう。
どうぞ。
では次です。
二十分待ちです。英語で、どうぞ。
さて、次の文に行く前に、この語彙を確認しましょう。
雰囲気、英語で言うと?
場所についてなら、atmosphereを使います。
では、atmosphereを使って、こちらを言ってみましょう。
音楽と雰囲気がいいですね。
さて、次の文に行く前にこの語彙を確認しましょう。
レストランでの席。
How do you say 席 in English?
英語では table を使って表現します。
例えばこの文です。
私たちの席は
あちらです。
Our table. 借りてください。
どうぞ。
この席はいいですね。
では続いて、実際に座ることについて、
スイート使います。
ということで、こちらを言ってみよう。
席につきましょう。
さあ、最後です。
レストランは見つけにくかったですか?
Hard to findを使ってどうぞ。
OK, how was your first round?
Did you try to say each one?
一回目の挑戦はいかがでしたか?
では、ここで回答例をチェックしましょう。
そして今週は少しレベルアップして英語での解説も混ぜてみます。
So now, you can check your answers with mine.
Okay, listen closely.
このアイロランド料理店は味がありますね。
This Irish restaurant is charming.
味がある。
In English, it can be charming.
Charming is not just 可愛らしい or 愛嬌がある。
お店についてなら、味がある。こじまりしている。
All right, here's the next one.
あまり知られていませんが、料理がおいしいです。
It's not very well known, but the food is good.
You can also say, it's not very famous, but the food is good.
For おいしい, good.
For とてもおいしい、グルメ級のおいしさ、delicious.
Okay, here's the next one.
レストランの外にいつも行列ができています。
There's always a long line outside the restaurant.
行列のできるお店。
In America, it's line.
In other countries, they use the word queue.
There's always a long queue outside the restaurant.
Either one is fine.
All right, here's the next one.
20分待ちです。
There's a 20-minute wait.
You can also say, there's a 20-minute wait for a table.
All right, here's the next one.
音楽と雰囲気がいいですね。
I like the music and the atmosphere.
For a place, we use atmosphere.
Mood is usually a personal feeling.
So, I like the music and the atmosphere.
All right, here's the next one.
Watashitachi no seki wa achira desu.
Our table is over there.
In Japanese, when you talk about a restaurant, seki.
But in English, it's table.
Our table is over there.
And here's the next one with table.
Kono seki wa ii desu ne.
This is a good table.
Seki ni tsukimashou.
Let's have a seat.
You can also say let's sit down.
But instead of sit down, have a seat is a little softer way of saying 席につきましょう。
All right, here's the last one.
レストランは見つけにくかったですか?
Was the restaurant hard to find?
Okay, did you understand today's phrases?
それではみなさん、今学習した表現をテンポよくもう一度言ってみましょう。
We'll pick up the pace a little in round two.
Here we go.
このアイロランド料理店は味がありますね。
This Irish restaurant is charming.
あまり知られていませんが料理がおいしいです。
It's not very well known, but the food is good.
レストランの外にいつも行列ができています。
There's always a long line outside the restaurant.
20分待ちです。
There's a 20-minute wait.
Ongaku to fungiki ga ii desu ne.
I like the music and the atmosphere.
Watashitachi no seki wa achira desu.
Our table is over there.
Kono seki wa ii desu ne.
This is a good table.
Let's have a seat.
Was the restaurant hard to find?
Okay, time's up.
Well, how did you do?
All right, everyone, keep practicing.
And get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Eikaiwa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.